{
    "question": "91)  The  Central  government  approved  Rs  1,340  crore \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  129 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \nrecapitalisation  plan  to  help  which  type  of  banks",
    "answer": "  Regional \nRural Banks (RRBs) \n"
}{
    "question": "92)  Govt has planned recapitalization of RRBs to meet the CRAR \nrequirements  What  is  full  form  of  CRAR",
    "answer": "  Capital  to  Risk \nweighted Assets Ratio \n"
}{
    "question": "93)  What is the percentage of stake of the sponsoring bank in the \ncapital of the RRB",
    "answer": " 35% \n"
}{
    "question": "94)  What is the percentage of stake of the central government in the \ncapital of the RRB",
    "answer": " 50% \n"
}{
    "question": "95)  Rajyogini  Dadi  Janki,  who  passed  away  recently,  was  the \nspiritual  head  of  which world  famous  spiritual  organisation",
    "answer": " \nBrahma Kumaris Sansthan \n"
}{
    "question": "96)  The World Theatre Day is observed on which day of March",
    "answer": " 23rd \n"
}{
    "question": "97)  Which US defence force deployed its Advanced Extremely High \nFrequency (AEHF) satellite to provide secure communications \nfor the US military and its allies",
    "answer": "  US Space Force \n"
}{
    "question": "98)  Government announced the \u2018Garib Kalyan Package\u2019 for helping \nthe poor people amidst the Corona crisis  What is its amount",
    "answer": "  \nRs 1o70 lakh crore \n"
}{
    "question": "99)  Under which new government scheme 80 crore poor people will \nbe given 5 kg Wheat or 5 kg Rice and one kg pulse for 3 months",
    "answer": "  \nPradhan Mantri Garib Kalyan Anna Yojana \n"
}{
    "question": "100)   Government has announced Rs____ lakh per person insurance \ncover for all employees working in the medical field for next \nthree months",
    "answer": "  50 \n"
}{
    "question": "101)  Indian scientists have developed \u2018MACS 4028\u2019, a biofortified \nhigh-protein variety of which crop",
    "answer": "  Wheat \n"
}{
    "question": "102)  Which  country  hosted  the  firstever  G-20  virtual  summit \nthrough video conference",
    "answer": " Saudi Arabia \n"
}{
    "question": "103)  Name the doe-eyed star of 1950s and \u201860s Hindi movies such as \nAan, Barsaat and Deedar,  who  died recently  after  prolonged \nillness",
    "answer": "  Nimmi \n"
}{
    "question": "104)  Name the artist and architect renowned for his versatility across \ndifferent mediums, who passed away recently in New Delhi",
    "answer": "  \nSatish Gujral \n"
}{
    "question": "105)  Which global rating agency slashed its estimate of India's GDP \ngrowth during the 2020 calendar year to 2o5 per cent, from an \nearlier estimate of 5o3 per cent",
    "answer": "  Moody's Investors Service  \n"
}{
    "question": "106)  The Monetary Policy Committee of RBI headed by its Governor \nShaktikanta Das announced on March 27 a cut in benchmark \ninterest rate, Repo Rate by _____ basis points to 4o40 per cent",
    "answer": "  \n75 \n"
}{
    "question": "107)  RBI reduced the Cash Reserve Ratio (CRR) of all banks by \n______ basis points to 3 per cent with effect from March 28 for 1 \nyear",
    "answer": "  100 \n"
}{
    "question": "108)  What  is  the  new  reverse  repo  rate  under  the  LAF  after  a \nreduction of 90 basis points",
    "answer": "  4% \n"
}{
    "question": "109)  Which  oil  company has become  the  1st  Indian  company  to \nbegin  supply  of  BS-VI  fuel  across  its  28,000  petrol  pumps",
    "answer": "  \nIndian Oil Corporation Ltd \n"
}{
    "question": "110)  The Reserve Bank of India has decided to extend the _________  \n_______ classification for bank loans to Non-Banking Financial \nCompanies (NBFCs) for on-lending, for FY 2020-21",
    "answer": "  Priority \nsector \n"
}{
    "question": "111)  Which State Police has become the first to be equipped with \ntaser guns as a part of their modernization drive to ensure public \nsafety and security",
    "answer": "  Gujarat \n"
}{
    "question": "112)  Which  gas  is  used  in  the  Taser  guns  to  fire  the  darts",
    "answer": "  \nCompressed Nitrogen \n"
}{
    "question": "113)  Famous \u2018Abel Prize\u2019 is given for outstanding achievement in \nwhich field",
    "answer": "  Mathematics \n"
}{
    "question": "114)  Government of which country has instituted the Abel Prize",
    "answer": "  \nNorway \n"
}{
    "question": "115)  Japan's  Prime  Minister  and  the  head  of  the  International \nOlympic Committee, Shinzo Abe announced to postpone the \nTokyo 2020 Games by how many months",
    "answer": "  12 \n"
}{
    "question": "116)  In the 124-year old history of the Olympics, the games have \nbeen cancelled how many times",
    "answer": "  Three \n"
}{
    "question": "117)  World Tuberculosis Day is observed on which day of March",
    "answer": " 24 \n"
}{
    "question": "118)  World Tuberculosis Day is observed with the support of which \nUN organisation",
    "answer": " WHO \u2013 World Health Organisation \n"
}{
    "question": "119)  What is the theme for this year\u2019s World Tuberculosis Day",
    "answer": " It\u2019s \nTime \n"
}{
    "question": "120)  Name  the  scientist  who  discovered  the  Tuberculosis  causing \nbacteria",
    "answer": "  Dr Robert Koch    \n"
}{
    "question": "121)  Name  the  Indian  mountaineer  who  entered  \u2018Limca  Book  of \nRecords\u2019  for  his  extraordinary  achievement  of  becoming  the \nfirst Indian to climb the highest volcanoes of each of the 7 \ncontinents",
    "answer": "  Satyarup Siddhanta \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  131 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \n"
}{
    "question": "122)  Who took the oath of Chief Minister for the fourth time in \nMadhya Pradesh",
    "answer": "  Shivraj Singh Chouhan \n"
}{
    "question": "123)  March 23 is celebrated as Shaheed Diwas every year to pay \ntribute to which three martyrs",
    "answer": " Bhagat Singh, Sukhdev Thapar, \nand Shivaram Rajguru \n"
}{
    "question": "124)  World Meteorological Day is observed on March 23 to highlight \nwhich important issue",
    "answer": "  Climate related issues \n"
}{
    "question": "125)  What is the theme for this year\u2019s World Water Day",
    "answer": "  Water and \nclimate change \n"
}{
    "question": "126)  On which day of March we celebrate World Water Day",
    "answer": "  March \n22 \n"
}{
    "question": "127)  For what purpose Small Industries Development Bank of India \n(SIDBI) plans to start Swavalamban Express on June 05, 2020",
    "answer": "  \nTo promote budding business aspirants and entrepreneurs \n"
}{
    "question": "128)  Where are the headquarters of Small Industries Development \nBank of India (SIDBI)",
    "answer": "  Lucknow \n"
}{
    "question": "129)  Who is the current Charman & Managing Director of SIDBI",
    "answer": " \nMohmmad Mustafa \n"
}{
    "question": "130)  When do we celebrate the International Day for the Elimination \nof Racial Discrimination",
    "answer": "  March 21  \n"
}{
    "question": "131)  What is the theme for this year\u2019s World Down Syndrome Day \nobserved on March 21",
    "answer": "  We Decide   \n"
}{
    "question": "132)  On which date we observe World Poetry Day",
    "answer": "  March 21 \n"
}{
    "question": "133)  Which  international  day  is  observed  every  year  to  raise \nawareness about the importance of the household sparrow and \nthe other common birds to urban environments, and the threats \nto their populations",
    "answer": " The World Sparrow Day  \n"
}{
    "question": "134)  As per the World Happiness Report 2020 released by the United \nNations, India stands at which rank in world",
    "answer": "  144th \n"
}{
    "question": "135)  Which  country  topped  the  rankings  given  by  the  World \nHappiness Report 2020",
    "answer": "  Finland \n"
}{
    "question": "136)  Name the legendary Indian footballer who died in Kolkata after \nbattling prolonged illness",
    "answer": " P K Banerjee \n"
}{
    "question": "137)  The Defence Ministry signed a capital acquisition contract with \nwhich country for procurement of 16,479 Negev 7o62x51 mm \nlight machine guns (LMGs)",
    "answer": "  Israel \n"
}{
    "question": "138)  A bench of NCLAT has been established in Chennai to cater to \nthe needs of south based clients Expand the term NCLAT",
    "answer": "  \nNational Company Law Appellate Tribunal \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  132 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \n"
}{
    "question": "139)  OFB  -Ordnance  Factory  Board,  the  2nd  largest  defence \nequipment manufacturer in Asia, has its headquarters in which \ncity",
    "answer": "  Kolkata \n"
}{
    "question": "140)  What  is  the  name  of  the  OFB  HQs  in  Kolkata",
    "answer": "    Aayudh \nBhawan \n"
}{
    "question": "141)  The Chameli Devi Award is conferred upon women for showing \nexcellence in which field",
    "answer": " Journalism \n"
}{
    "question": "142)  A  roll-on-roll  off  cum  passenger  ferry  service,  was  recently \nlaunched between Mumbai and which other city",
    "answer": "   Mandwa \n"
}{
    "question": "143)  Which apex authority recently ruled that women cannot be \ndenied permanent commission in the Navy",
    "answer": "  Supreme Court \n"
}{
    "question": "144)  A tiny island country in the South Pacific Ocean has become the \nworld\u2019s first whole country to be recognised as a \u2018Dark Sky \nPlace\u2019 Name it",
    "answer": "  Nieu \n"
}{
    "question": "145)  Who has been appointed as the new MD and CEO of the Yes \nBank",
    "answer": "  Prashant Kumar \n"
}{
    "question": "146)  Which national day is observed celebrate delivery of the first \ndose of Oral Polio Vaccine in India on March 16, 1995",
    "answer": " National \nVaccination Day \n"
}{
    "question": "147)  Name the former Chief Justice of India who has recently been \nnominated to Rajya Sabha",
    "answer": "  Justice Ranjan Gogoi \n"
}{
    "question": "148)  The Central Sanskrit University Bill 2019 was passed recently \nby the Parliament to provide Central University status to how \nmany universities in India",
    "answer": "  Three \n"
}{
    "question": "149)  Name the ace Indian paddler who ended his decade-long wait for \na title by winning the ITTF Challenger Plus Oman Open (Table \nTennis) in Muscat, Oman",
    "answer": "   Achanta Sharath Kamal \n"
}{
    "question": "150)  Noted philanthropist and IT magnate, Bill Gates was in news \nrecently for what reason",
    "answer": "  He stepped down from Microsoft\u2019s \nBoard of Directors \n"
}{
    "question": "151)  Muhyiddin Yassin has been appointed as the Prime Minister of \nwhich country",
    "answer": "  Malaysia \n"
}{
    "question": "152)  The First Khelo India University Games were hosted by which \nstate",
    "answer": " Odisha \n"
}{
    "question": "153)  Indian Railways launched its first \u201cRestaurant on Wheels\u201d at \nwhich railway station",
    "answer": "  Asansol, West Bengal \n"
}{
    "question": "154)  On which date we celebrate Zero Discrimination Day",
    "answer": "  March 1 \n"
}{
    "question": "155)  What is the name of the welfare programme launched to provide \ngood  nutritional  food  tp  pregnant  mothers",
    "answer": "    Suposhit  Maa \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  133 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \nAbhiyaan \n"
}{
    "question": "156)  The United States recently signed a historic peace agreement \nwith which big militant group",
    "answer": "  Taliban \n"
}{
    "question": "157)  Which militant outfit is formally known as the Islamic Emirate \nof Afghanistan",
    "answer": "  Taliban \n"
}{
    "question": "158)  DRDO  in  collaboration  with  Indian  Institute  of  Science, \nBengaluru  has  developed  a  new  explosive  detection  device \nRaIDer-X  for  what  purpose",
    "answer": "   To  detect  explosives  from  a \ndistance \n"
}{
    "question": "159)  Which International day is observed on March 3 for raising \nawareness  about  flora  and  fauna  and  the  dependability  of \nhumans on their surroundings and the environment",
    "answer": "  World \nWildlife Day \n"
}{
    "question": "160)  The Government of India has declared the National Chambal \nSanctuary an eco-sensitive zone It lies in which state",
    "answer": "  Madhya \nPradesh \n"
}{
    "question": "161)  Dr  Ajay  Bhushan  Pandey  has  been  given  charge  of  which \nimportant office in the Finance Ministry",
    "answer": "  Finance Secretary \n"
}{
    "question": "162)   Which are the two places nominated by the government for \ninclusion  in  the  World  Heritage  List  2020,  maintained  by \nUNESCO",
    "answer": "    Dholvira  and  Forts  and  Monuments  of  Deccan \nSultanate \n"
}{
    "question": "163)  Dholavira, an ancient site of Indus Valley Civilization is located \nin which state",
    "answer": "  Gujarat \n"
}{
    "question": "164)  India bagged a $ 40 million deal to supply 4 indigenously built \nradars  (capable  of  locating  weapons)  to  which  European \ncountry",
    "answer": "  Armenia \n"
}{
    "question": "165)  Assembly of which state went paperless on March 2 with the \nimplementation  of  National  e-Vidhan  Application  (NeVA)",
    "answer": "  \nArunachal Pradesh \n"
}{
    "question": "166)  Which  union  ministry  is  responsible  for  implementation  of \nNational  e-Vidhan  Application",
    "answer": "    Ministry  of  Parliamentary \nAffairs \n"
}{
    "question": "167)  Who is the Minister of Parliamentary Affairs",
    "answer": "  Pralhad Joshi \n"
}{
    "question": "168)  What is the name of the scheme that aims to replace all level \ncrossings on National Highways with road over bridges or under \nbridges",
    "answer": "  Setu Bhartam \n"
}{
    "question": "169)  Name the former UN chief, who led the world body during the \nIran-Iraq  war  and  the  civil  war  in  El  Salvador,  who  died \nrecently",
    "answer": "  Javier Perez de Cuellar \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  134 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \n"
}{
    "question": "170)  India observes National Safety Day on which date",
    "answer": "  March 4 \n"
}{
    "question": "171)  Which hilly state  of  India  has declared to shift its  summer \ncapital to Gairsain",
    "answer": "  Uttarakhand \n"
}{
    "question": "172)  On March 1, we celebrate World _____  ______ Day to highlight \nthe importance of civil protection",
    "answer": "  Civil Defence \n"
}{
    "question": "173)  What was the theme for this year\u2019s World Civil Defence Day",
    "answer": "  \nChildren\u2019s safety, our responsibility \n"
}{
    "question": "174)  India celebrates Jan Aushadhi Diwas on which day of March",
    "answer": " \n7th \n"
}{
    "question": "175)  International Women's Day is observed on which date",
    "answer": "  March 8 \n"
}{
    "question": "176)  Dhruv Batra Player of the Year Award is given for outstanding \nperformance in which field",
    "answer": "  Hockey \n"
}{
    "question": "177)  Who won this year\u2019s Dhruv Batra Player of the Year Award for \nmen",
    "answer": "  Manpreet Singh \n"
}{
    "question": "178)  Who won this year\u2019s Dhruv Batra Player of the Year Award for \nwomen",
    "answer": "  Rani Rampal \n"
}{
    "question": "179)  Denys Shmygal was elected as the new _________ of Ukraine",
    "answer": "  \nPrime Minister \n"
}{
    "question": "181)  Finals of the ICC Women\u2019s T20 World Cup 2020 were held in \nwhich city",
    "answer": "  Melbourne, Australia \n"
}{
    "question": "182)   Securities and Exchange Board of India (SEBI) has launched a \nmobile  application  \u2018Sebi  SCORES\u2019  for  what  purpose",
    "answer": "    To \nfacilitate  online  filing  of  investors  grievances  through  their \nsmartphones\n"
}{
    "question": "183)  What is the full form of the acronym SCORES",
    "answer": "  Sebi Complaints \nRedress System \n"
}{
    "question": "185)  \u201cChapchar Kut\u201d is the most joyful and biggest spring festival of \nwhich Indian state",
    "answer": "  Mizoram \n"
}{
    "question": "186)   Which state government has asked the temple administrators \nin  the state to obtain a \u2018BHOG\u2019 certificate from FSSAI (Food \nSafety  and  Standards  Authority  of  India)  for  the  \u2018prasad\u2019 \ndistributed by them",
    "answer": "  Tamil Nadu \n"
}{
    "question": "187)  What is the name of the Mizoram\u2019s popular bamboo folk dance",
    "answer": "  \nCheraw \n"
}{
    "question": "189)  Which great Indian king was named as the 'greatest leader ever' \nin the world in a survey conducted by BBC World History \nMagazine",
    "answer": "  Maharaja Ranjit Singh \n"
}{
    "question": "190)  Pritzker Prize is given for outstanding achievement in which \nfield",
    "answer": "  Architecture \n"
}{
    "question": "191)  What  is  the amount  of cash  award  given with  the  Pritzker \nPrize",
    "answer": "  $ 1,00,000/= \n"
}{
    "question": "192)  What is one word that describes a disease that is spreading \nbetween people in multiple countries around the world at the \nsame time",
    "answer": "  Pandemic \n"
}{
    "question": "193)  The  World  Kidney  Day  is  observed  on  which  Thursday  of \nMarch",
    "answer": "  Second \n"
}{
    "question": "194)   Who is popularly known as the Father of Green Revolution in \nIndia",
    "answer": "  Dr M S Swaminathan \n"
}{
    "question": "195)  Dr  M  S  Swaminathan  award  is  given  for  outstanding \nperformance in which field",
    "answer": "  Agriculture \n"
}{
    "question": "196)  Which  state  has  topped  the  list  for  domestic  solar  rooftop \ninstallations,  accounting  for  about  64%  of  the  total  77,950 \ndomestic solar installations in the country",
    "answer": "  Gujarat \n"
}{
    "question": "197)  Who is the winner of the first BBC Indian Sportswoman of the \nYear Award \u2013 2019",
    "answer": "  P V Sindhu \n"
}{
    "question": "198)  India  is  the  world\u2019s  second  largest  arms  importer  Which \ncountry is at first spot",
    "answer": " Saudi Arabia \n"
}{
    "question": "199)  The  World  Bank  approved  a  $80  million  loan  to  the \n____________  government  to  improve  water  management \npractices  and  increase  agricultural  productivity",
    "answer": "    Himachal \nPradesh \n"
}{
    "question": "201)  The World Health Organization, WHO launched an emergency \ntask  force  \u201cCOVID  Action  Platform\u201d  in  collaboration  with \nwhich other organisation",
    "answer": "  World Economic Forum \n"
}{
    "question": "202)  In a big decision towards \"Customer First Approach '', which \nbank waived minimum balance requirement for its savings bank \ncustomers",
    "answer": "   State Bank of India \n"
}{
    "question": "203)  The  4th  Inclusive  Internet  Index  2020  compiled  by  the \nEconomist Intelligence Unit (EIU), London has placed India at \nwhich rank",
    "answer": "  46th \nDownload Gyanm App from Play Store  136 \n (Stay Updated on Govt Jobs: WhatsApp 'Hello' to 9117-343434) \n"
}{
    "question": "204)  The government has announced to hold a CET for recruitment \nin railways, banks and lower levels of the Central government \nWhat is the full form of CET",
    "answer": " Common Eligibility Test \n"
}{
    "question": "205)  Which International Day is observed on March 15 to promote \nbasic rights of consumers and to ensure that these rights are \nrespected and protected",
    "answer": "  The World Consumer Rights Day \n"
}{
    "question": "206)  For the first time in India, the Department of Posts introduced \na  free  digital  parcel  locker  service  in  __________  to  enable \ncustomers  to  collect  their  consignment  from  specified  post \noffices at their convenience",
    "answer": "  Kolkata "
}